By now, you're probably knows that there
is a sales order agent in the Business
Central, which should help you to
monitor sales orders or sales inquiries
and process them.
You probably interested, how does it
work for my company? And let me show you
how you can easily experiment with it
with low risk.
So, first, we can find the icon with
sales order agent and choose activate.
And the first tab, you can see something
new.
You can see the tried out section, which
allows you to create a task without even
connecting to the inbox to the real
inbox.
And then experiment on how things works.
So, here it will show you something
where you can imitate received email.
So, you can populate uh
email
from your customer or select one from
existing contact.
And then you can either put text
manually or use one of the predefined
templates with or without attachment.
Mail with attachment and you can scroll
down. Attachment is indeed added. You
can also add something manually if you
wish.
Choose okay.
And update to activate the agent.
Yeah, we are not monitoring inbox at
this stage because we are just curious
how it works
uh with the predefined template. You can
see that system already showed that one
email is received from Robert Towers.
This is exactly our template.
Now, we need to review it.
And see that customer is identified.
There is indeed some attachment, which
we can see it.
Other ones were filtered out as
non-relevant.
So, we press continue and let agent to
process this inquiry.
It might take
some time for agent to actually perform
the task and generate the
draft reply. Let's take a look at what
it proposed.
Agent figured out the customer. Already
we know it on the first from the first
steps, but it also found all items,
prices, and prepared and attached the
sales quote. Of course, we cannot
continue. We cannot send this email
because we didn't connect the inbox at
this point of time, but we review the
email and make some notes.
So, probably right now we already know
what we want to improve in way how sales
order agent operates. So,
let's stop this specific task
and jump back to the configuration.
Because probably at this point of time
we already understand what's happening
and ready to try with real customer
inquiries. So, now it's good time to
connect to the real inboxes. I can
select my personal inbox or one of the
shared inboxes.
And if I select my personal inbox
or even if I select shared inbox and I'm
still experimenting with agent and try
to evaluate it, it is very good idea to
use a dedicated folder. Not inbox, but
you can create a dedicated folder where
you can put preselected email messages
from your real customers for which you
want to experiment uh
and see how agent can process them.
All right. So, now we're activating real
inbox. The next step, probably we don't
want to review all incoming messages,
especially if they're coming from
existing customers. So, I will activate
like no review. I don't need it. I can
decide on how to process availability.
Do I want to experiment with real
availability right now or maybe later or
should I also use a capable to promise?
I can also decide to skip quote part and
just send orders to the customer.
Let's press update and send some email
to to experiment and see what's
happened.
This is email I prepared and I'm sending
it to my email address which sales order
agent monitors. I press send and once I
will receive it in my Outlook, I will
transfer it to the dedicated folder.
We received email with a attachment
content etc. And now we
transferring it to the sales request
folder.
Now it is here ready to be processed.
Now switching back to Business Central
where we can see that sales order agent
already detected that there is a new
email in this folder and start and start
to process it immediately because we
configured it that for known customers
we do not need to review incoming mails.
But meanwhile we can still open it and
see that it actually matches and
it has customer information, it has
inquiry and three attachments. Notice
that two of them are already marked as
non-relevant by sales order agent
because it's terms and condition and
privacy policy which apparently our
customer always attach to the email but
the content is in this sample order PDF.
But back to the timeline.
Agent was working and I was working on
my task but I got notification that
something happened and ready for my
review.
Let's click review task and I can see
that outgoing email is ready.
Ready for my review.
Again, nothing leaves
Business Central without human review
means my review. So I can see that sales
order agent actually prepared the
document
and
of this type time, it is sales order
confirmation.
So, now I can I can send it to my
customer.
So, now you can see that you can easily
experiment and see if sales order agent
works for your business or not and tune
it to make sure that it fits exactly as
it needed.
Thank you.